toysrus.ca 2018-05-12

# Toys"R"Us/Babies"R"Us : Help Desk

**The "R" Us Family Privacy Policy**

* * *

  1. WHAT DOES THIS "R" US FAMILY PRIVACY POLICY COVER?
  2. WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT?
  3. CHILDREN'S PRIVACY
  4. HOW DO WE USE AND SHARE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?
  5. HOW IS YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION PROTECTED?
  6. WHERE IS YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION PROCESSED AND STORED?
  7. HOW CAN YOU ACCESS YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?
  8. WHAT ARE COOKIES, WEB BEACONS AND FLASH COOKIES, AND HOW DO WE USE THEM?
  9. HOW THE "R" US FAMILY USES YOUR INFORMATION FOR ADVERTISING
  10. WHAT ABOUT LINKED SITES?
  11. HOW TO CONTACT US
  12. REVISIONS TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY
  13. WEBSITE USE AGREEMENT

**1\. What does this "R" Us Family Privacy Policy cover?**

The "R" Us Family includes Toys "R" Us, Inc.; Babiesrus.com, LLC; Toys "R" Us (Canada) Ltd.; and their affiliates (collectively, the ""R" Us Family members" or the ""R" Us Family").

This Privacy Policy outlines "R" Us Family practices regarding personal information collected (a) on our corporate website online at www.toysruscanada.ca or www.toysrusinc.ca (the ""R" Us Site"); (b) online at www.toysrus.ca, www.babiesrus.ca, www.babies-r-us.ca, www.babiesruscanada.ca, www.kidsrus.ca, www.kids-r-us.ca, www.giftsrus.ca, www.sportsrus.ca, www.imaginarium.ca, www.rzone.ca, www.rzonecentral.ca, www.mybabiesrus.ca and any other websites and/or apps operated by Toys "R" Us (Canada) Ltd. (collectively, the "Online Store") (the "R" Us Site and the Online Store referred to collectively as "our websites"); (c) when you call, e-mail or otherwise communicate with Toys "R" Us (Canada) Ltd., including at our call centers; and (d) at Toys "R" Us retail stores in Canada (the "Retail Stores"). Nothing in this Privacy Policy, or otherwise, will create, or add to, any right or claim (whether legal, equitable or otherwise) that any individual or person may have at law, or otherwise, against any of the "R" Us Family members' respective directors, officers, employees, agents or representatives (collectively, the "'R" Us Family Representatives"); nor will the existence of this Privacy Policy or its application impose any obligations or liability upon the "R" Us Family Representatives, or add to any such obligation or liability, that the "R" Us Family Representatives do not already otherwise have to any individual or person at law or otherwise.

**YOUR CONSENT**

BY SUBMITTING PERSONAL INFORMATION TO THE "R" US FAMILY MEMBERS OR THEIR RESPECTIVE SERVICE PROVIDERS OR AGENTS VIA OUR WEBSITES OR AT THE RETAIL STORES, OR THROUGH OTHER INTERACTIONS WITH US AS DESCRIBED IN SECTION 2 BELOW, YOU CONSENT TO OUR COLLECTION, USE AND DISCLOSURE OF SUCH PERSONAL INFORMATION FOR THE PURPOSES DESCRIBED IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND AS PERMITTED OR REQUIRED BY LAW.

If you provide us with personal information concerning another individual, you represent and warrant that you have all necessary authority and/or have obtained all necessary consents from such individual to enable us to collect, use and disclose such personal information for the purposes set forth in this Privacy Policy.

Subject to legal and contractual requirements and reasonable notice, you may withdraw your consent at any time; however, without such consent, "R" Us Family members may limit the services or products they are able to provide to you. You may also withdraw your consent for:

  * **_Mail marketing, Telephone marketing and Quality control communications._** You may decide that you prefer that "R" Us Family members not use your personal information to promote new and/or additional products and services which may be of interest to you and refuse that an "R" Us Family member contact you by mail or telephone for marketing purposes or by email or telephone for quality control purposes. If this is the case, you may advise us by calling 1-800-TOYSRUS (1-800-869-7787) and asking for assistance through a customer service representative. 
  * **_Commercial Electronic Messages._** You can always limit commercial electronic messages that "R" Us Family members send to you. To opt-out of commercial electronic messages, simply click the link labeled "unsubscribe" at the bottom of any email that a "R" Us Family member sends to you, follow the other instructions provided or call 1-800-TOYSRUS (1-800-869-7787) and ask for assistance through a customer service representative. Please note that even if you opt-out of these promotional communications, the "R" Us Family may still need to contact you with important information about a purchase made from the "R" Us Family.

Once you withdraw your consent, your personal information may be retained in the "R" Us Family database to ensure that we honour your privacy requests to opt-out of certain communications and for record-keeping purposes. 

 BACK TO TOP

**2\. What information do we collect?**

As used in this Privacy Policy, "personal information" is information about an identifiable individual, as defined in privacy laws applicable to the "R" Us Family. Personal information does not include aggregated information that does not allow an individual to be identified. For purposes of this Privacy Policy, information regarding your children that you (the parent) provide to the "R" Us Family is treated in the same manner as information collected about you. Please see Section 3 below for further information regarding children's privacy.

(a)     _Information You Give Us_

The "R" Us Family members collect personal information (including, without limitation, names, addresses, telephone numbers and email addresses) that you provide when you: (i) visit the Online Store and the Retail Stores; (ii) create or edit your Registries and Wish Lists; (iii) register your R Club card or otherwise participate in the R Club loyalty program; (iv) participate in a contest, sweepstakes or other promotion; (v) sign up for and/or fill out a survey or questionnaire; (vi) sign-up for email and/or SMS news and alerts (or other commercial electronic messages); (vii) contact an "R" Us Family member (by email or otherwise); (viii) contact an "R" Us Family customer service representative; (ix) otherwise interact with an "R" Us Family member; or ( x) provide product reviews and/or feedback.

(b)     _Automatic Information Collection_

Each time you visit the "R" Us Site or the Online Store, the web server automatically collects certain types of information, including your Internet service provider's address, your Internet protocol or IP address, the web page from which you logged in, your web browser software, the language settings on your web browser, and a record of your activity while visiting the "R" Us Site or the Online Store. "R" Us Family members may use cookies, pixel tags, browser analysis tools, server logs, web beacons and other similar technologies that allow us to know if a particular web page was visited, an email opened, links in the email utilized or if the advertisements on the "R" Us Site or Online Store were effective. In some instances, these technologies may allow us to match activities with particular users. Please see Sections 8 and 9 below for further information about such technologies.

While using "R" Us Family apps, including the Play Chaser app, we will collect unique device identifiers and information concerning the game activities and usage of the app in connection with such unique device identifier, in order to be able to operate and improve the app. However, this information cannot identify you as an individual since the "R" Us Family does not have the capacity to link, combine or match such information with other personal information of an app user.

 BACK TO TOP

**3\. Children's Privacy**

The "R" Us Site, Online Store and Retail Stores do not knowingly solicit or collect personal information from children under the age of 13. We encourage parents of children under the age of 13 to regularly check and monitor their children's use of e-mail and the "R" Us Family websites.

 BACK TO TOP

**4\. How do we use and share your personal information?**

_Using Your Personal Information_

The "R" Us Family members collect, use and disclose personal information in accordance with applicable privacy laws and regulations.

Your personal information may be used by the "R" Us Family members and their agents and service providers: (a) to administer and enhance your guest and/or customer relationship with us, including to administer accounts, maintain gift registries, Wish Lists, R Club cards and the R Club loyalty program, to book Baby Registry or other appointments with a "R" Us Family member, monitor customer refunds, facilitate deliveries, administer our customer service centre, make and receive payments, and fulfill contractual obligations; (b) to understand your needs and preferences, respond to your requests and follow-up on, respond to and settle any complaints or inquiries you may have regarding our products, stores and/or services; (c) subject to your right to opt-out of such advertising (please refer to Section 9), to tailor offerings to you by delivering to you or allowing you to see certain advertising based on your interests, searches you perform, information you provide at the Retail Store, on the "R" Us Site or Online Store or your activity on our websites or other websites; (d) subject to your right to withdraw consent for such purposes, to communicate with you about products, services, special offerings and events or programs offered by the "R" Us Family members or their marketing partners that may be of interest to you; (e) subject to your right to withdraw consent for such purposes, to conduct surveys, contests and promotions; (f) to conduct research and statistical analysis; (g) to monitor communications to ensure the consistency and quality of the products and services of the "R" Us Family and its suppliers, distributors and other third parties with whom we have a commercial relationship; (h) to manage and develop the "R" Us Family businesses and operations; (i) to detect and protect the "R" Us Family and other third parties against error, negligence, breach of contract, theft, fraud and other illegal activity; (j) to comply with the "R" Us Family audit requirements, and to audit compliance with laws and the "R" Us Family corporate policies, procedures and contractual obligations; (k) to engage in due diligence and carry out business transactions that may involve the purchase, sale, lease, merger, amalgamation or any other type of acquisition, disposal, securitization or financing involving an "R" Us Family member; (l) as permitted by, and to comply with, applicable laws and regulations; and (m) for any other purpose to which you consent.

Only "R" Us Family Representatives who require your personal information in the performance of their duties will have access to your personal information. Notably, only "R" Us Family Representatives in the customer service department, who process online purchases, may have access to your credit card information.

_Sharing Your Personal Information_

"R" Us Family members will not license, sell or provide your personal information to any third party except as permitted by this Privacy Policy, as permitted or required by law, or with your consent. In addition to the purposes described above, the "R" Us Family shares your personal information as set forth below:

**With "R" Us Family Members.** Personal information collected by one member of the "R" Us Family will be used by that member in accordance with this Privacy Policy and may be shared with other "R" Us Family members for use only as permitted by law.

**With Our Agents and/or Service Providers.** "R" Us Family members may share your personal information with agents and service providers who provide services for, or administer activities on behalf of, the "R" Us Family (such as, but not limited to, authorization of credit card transactions, order fulfillment and delivery, sweepstakes, website maintenance and contests, marketing, advertising, data processing and storage, information technology and office services, auditors and professional advisors, and co-branded or joint product and service promotions). These agents and/or service providers are granted access to some or all of your personal information as necessary in order to provide the service and may use cookies and other automatic collection technologies (as described in further detail in Section 8 below) on our behalf. "R" Us Family members strive to protect personal information rendered accessible to agents and service providers by using contractual and other measures to restrict them from using your personal information in any manner other than as may be necessary to perform their mandate and/or services. We may also utilize agents and/or service providers to assist us in aggregating personal information. We may then share such aggregated information (but not personal information) with prospective marketing partners and advertisers.

**In Connection with Business Transactions.** In the event that a store, division or part or all of an "R" Us Family member (or the assets of one of those entities) is bought, sold, otherwise transferred or financed, or is in the process of a potential transaction, personal information may need to be disclosed under confidentiality restrictions to perform due diligence reviews. If the transaction proceeds, such personal information may be used and disclosed by the successor entity, provided such use and disclosure is in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If the transaction does not proceed, the "R" Us Family will require the potential purchaser not to use or disclose customer personal information, in any manner whatsoever, and to return or destroy such information.

**To Comply with Laws and Protect Against Loss.** A "R" Us Family member may also disclose your personal information when it determines that such disclosure is necessary to comply with applicable laws, and/or to detect and protect the "R" Us Family and other third parties against error, negligence, breach of contract, theft, fraud and other illegal activity, to comply with the "R" Us Family audit requirements, and to audit compliance with laws and the "R" Us Family corporate policies, procedures and contractual obligations, to the extent permitted by law. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection, credit risk reduction, debt collection, insurance coverage and in the course of investigating and resolving disputes and litigation.

**On Registries and Wish Lists.** Registries and Wish Lists are made available for viewing by others. If you create your Registry or Wish List in a Retail Store, your information may be accessible at the Online Store. If you create your Registry or Wish List at the Online Store, your Registry information will also be accessible at the Retail Stores.

 BACK TO TOP

**5\. How is your personal information protected?**

The "R" Us Family members use industry-standard security techniques on our websites to help protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of information collected from you at our websites. When you access your account information or transmit personal information to our websites, that information is stored on servers that our websites have attempted to secure from unauthorized access or intrusion. "Secure Socket Layer" software encrypts personal information you transmit to our websites. The "R" Us Family members cannot be and are not responsible for unauthorized access to information by hackers or others who have obtained such access through illegal measures.

"Phishing" is a scam designed to steal your personal information. If you receive an email that looks like it might be from a "R" Us Family member asking for your personal information, do not respond. The "R" Us Family members would not request your password, user name, credit card information, or other personal information through email.

 BACK TO TOP

**6\. Where is your personal information processed and stored?**

Your personal information is processed and stored at Toys "R" Us (Canada) Ltd.'s corporate headquarters located at 2777 Langstaff Road in Concord, Ontario, L4K 4M5, Canada, at Toys "R" Us, Inc.'s corporate headquarters located at One Geoffrey Way in Wayne, New Jersey, 07470-2030, U.S., or at other locations in Canada, the United States, India and certain countries in Europe. Where personal information is stored or processed outside of Canada, it is subject to the laws of that foreign jurisdiction, and may be accessible to that jurisdiction's governments, courts or law enforcement or regulatory agencies.

 BACK TO TOP

**7\. How can you access your personal information?**

Upon your written request to our Privacy Manager at Toys "R" Us (Canada) Ltd., 2777 Langstaff Road, Concord, Ontario, L4K 4M5, we will inform you of the existence, use and disclosure of your personal information by an "R" Us Family member, and subject to certain exceptions permitted by law, we will give you a reasonable opportunity to review your personal information collected by the applicable "R" Us Family member.

If at any time you want to update, change or correct the personal information that you submitted at the "R" Us Site or Online Store, you can adjust your communications preferences in the "Your Account" section of the Online Store or call 1-800-TOYSRUS (1-800-869-7787) and ask for assistance on how you may update, change or correct your information. If at any time you want to update or change the information that you submitted in one of the Retail Stores, you can call 1-800-TOYSRUS (1-800-869-7787) and ask for assistance.

 BACK TO TOP

**8\. What are cookies, web beacons and Flash Cookies, and how do we use them?**

When you visit the "R" Us Site and Online Store, the "R" Us Family collects certain information by automated means, using technologies such as cookies, pixel tags, browser analysis tools, server logs and web beacons.

Cookies are small text files containing a unique identification number that identifies your computer browser to our computers each time you visit one of our websites and collects certain technical information about your visit to our websites (such as the IP address at your computer, which browser you used to view our websites, the site you came from, keywords searched, the number of page views, and advertisements you have seen). When these technologies allow the "R" Us Family to match such information with particular users, we will treat all such information as personal information. In addition to the purposes identified in this Privacy Policy, the "R" Us Family may use cookie information to measure the use of our websites and to improve the functionality and content of our websites. In many cases, you can manage cookie preferences and opt-out of having cookies and other data collection technologies used by adjusting the settings on your browser. All browsers are different, so visit the "help" section of your browser to learn about cookie preferences and other privacy settings that may be available. If you refuse to accept cookies, you may not be able to participate in certain activities, view certain presentations or use certain features on our websites.

Pixel tags and web beacons are tiny graphic images placed on our website pages or in our emails that allow "R" Us Family members to determine whether you have performed a specific action. When you access these pages or open or click an email, the pixel tags and web beacons generate a notice of that action. These tools allow the "R" Us Family to measure response to our communications and improve our website pages and promotions.

"R" Us Family members also use Flash Cookies (also known as Local Stored Objects) and similar technologies to personalize and enhance your online experience, facilitate processes and personalize and store your settings. A Flash cookie is a small data file placed on a computer using Adobe® Flash® or a similar technology that may be built into your computer or downloaded or installed by you to your computer. They help "R" Us Family members improve our websites by measuring which areas are of greatest interest to customers. Flash cookies are different from browser cookies and are managed through a different interface than the one provided by your web browser. Click [HERE](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html) to learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies. If you disable Flash cookies, please be aware that you may not have access to certain feature and services.

 BACK TO TOP

**9\. How the "R" Us Family uses your information for advertising**

"R" Us family members do not allow third party cookies on their websites for purposes of delivering advertising based on preferences or interests known or inferred from the data collected for advertising purposes (often referred to as Online Behavioural Advertising or OBA). "R" Us Family members do, however, advertise their products and/or services on third party websites. We do not have access to, or control over, cookies or other features that advertisers and third party sites may use, and the information practices of these advertisers and third party websites are not covered by our Privacy Policy. Please contact them directly for more information about their privacy practices. For more information on your choices with cookies, please click HERE.

You can also generally opt-out of receiving personalized ads from third party advertisers and ad networks who are members of the Digital Advertising Alliance of Canada ("DAAC"). Please visit the DAAC opt-out page <http://youradchoices.ca/choices> for more information.

**10\. What about linked sites?**

The "R" Us Site and Online Store may contain links to other websites, including content from other websites that is occasionally framed within the "R" Us Site or the Online Store. Other websites may collect personal information as well as information about your use of the "R" Us Site or Online Store. The "R" Us Family does not have access to, or control over, cookies or other features that third party websites may use. Please note that the privacy policies applicable to the collection of personal information on those other websites may be different from this one, and the "R" Us Family has no control or responsibility for the privacy practices of third party websites. You are advised to review the privacy policy of any website linked to, or framed within, the "R" Us Site or the Online Store prior to providing any information on or to that website.

 BACK TO TOP

**11\. How to contact us**

If you have questions or concerns regarding policies and practices of "R"Us Family members and/or their service providers in respect of the collection, storage, use and disclosure of personal information, please send an email to privacymanager_canada@toysrus.com, call 1-800-TOYSRUS (1-800-869-7787) or write to our Privacy Manager at Toys "R" Us (Canada) Ltd., 2777 Langstaff Road, Concord, Ontario, L4K 4M5.

 BACK TO TOP

**12\. Revisions to this Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy may be updated and revised from time to time. If we make a change to this Privacy Policy, we will post an updated policy on our websites and in our Retail Stores, and the updated policy will be available on request by sending an email to privacymanager_canada@toysrus.com, by calling 1-800-TOYSRUS (1-800-869-7787) or by writing to our Privacy Manager at Toys "R" Us (Canada) Ltd., 2777 Langstaff Road, Concord, Ontario, L4K 4M5. This policy was last revised on October 12, 2017.

 BACK TO TOP

**13\. Website Use Agreement**

The Website Use Agreement governing your use of this website (which may be viewed by clicking [HERE](http://www.toysrus.ca/helpdesk/panel/index.jsp?display=safety&subdisplay=terms&overrideStore=TRUSCA&locale=en_CA)) contains important provisions, including provisions disclaiming, limiting or excluding the liability of the "R" Us Family members for your use of our websites and provisions determining the applicable law and exclusive jurisdiction for the resolution of any disputes regarding your use of our websites. Each of those provisions are incorporated by reference into this Privacy Policy, apply to any disputes that may arise in relation to this Privacy Policy and the collection, use and disclosure of your personal information by the "R" Us Family members and are of the same force and effect as if they had been reproduced directly in this Privacy Policy.

 BACK TO TOP

_Effective Date of Privacy Policy: October 12, 2017_

Toys"R"Us (Canada) Ltd. 2777 Langstaff Road, Concord ON L4K 4M5, Tel: 1 800 TOYSRUS, Email: [can_customerservice@toysrus.com](mailto:can_customerservice@toysrus.com)

© 2018 Toys"R"Us (Canada) Ltd. All Rights reserved. Toys”R”Us, Babies”R”Us are registered trademarks of Toys”R”Us (Canada) Ltd. Use of this site signifies your acceptance of Toys"R"Us Website Terms and Conditions and Privacy Policy.
